

# **Ahsan Javed**

03244772022 ahsanjaveduog@gmail.com

## **ABOUT ME**

Currently pursuing MS from UET, Lhr. Also working in Atlas Insurance for almost 2years, part of one large-scale project, and also build 3 medium-sized projects in my current organization. Have a keen interest in Mobile application development and IT management. Also, get a diploma in Android Development from EVS, CEH from Corvit Systems, and Laravel Development from PNY Trainings.

#### **SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES**

- Tools: Android Studio, Eclipse, Unity, Visual Studio Code
- Framework: Laravel
- Database: SQLite, Firebase(cloud), MySQL
- Languages: Java, C#, Php
- Others: JSON, XML, Firebase, Third Party Apis, Rest Apis

## **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

University of Engineering and Technology, Lahore. MS in Computer Science 2020 - 2022

University of Gujrat, Lhr Campus. BS in Software Engineering 2014 - 2018

## **WORK HISTORY**

## **Assistant IT Manager**

Atlas Group

February 2020 to Present

- Developed user-friendly android applications for the client.
- Developed web portal in laravel framework.
- Validated completed Application including testing and debugging of code.
- Parse the data in JSON form using Volley and Rest Apis.
- Able to integrate the push notification module using FCM HTTP protocol.

# **Android Developer**

Absomech

January 2019 to January 2020

- Successfully developed the 3 large-scale, userfriendly, ultra-high performance android applications.
- Able to integrate the third-party API and parse the data from JSON into the application.
- Converted the PSD design into mobile UI using XML.
- Able to store and fetch the data into the cloud(Firebase).
- Also used the SQLite database for managing a large amount of data.
- Used new coded solutions that increase the application performance.
- Integrated ad networks like Admob, unity ads, Chartboost, startApp ads
- Published apps on the play store

# **PROJECTS**

## Appraisal Portal

As I work in a Group, management wants a portal (build on Laravel Framework) by which they can easily estimate the progress of their employees and their next year's objectives also they can check the last year's achievements.

#### HACPL

It connects with the server using Restful Apis, The Pie Charts and Line Graphs show the business which enhances the usability of the management users. It also contains different reports example, date wise vehicle business or development officer incentives, also shows the dealership business status.

• Restaurant Order App (Freelance)

This app automates the customer service, customers can select their product from the device placed on their tables and the chef received their order and time of order.

Surveyor App

When the claim enters into a portal, then the notification is received in an app, by using this app, the surveyor visits the location and provides necessary documents and estimates loss, and files the PLR form.

• Crystal Solution App (Freelance)

In which the company wants a product by which they can locate and customer and collect the monthly fee of their product. The goal is to make a product for collectors to ease their work and make an environment paperless.

Atlas Unify

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pk.atlas.ail.atlasunify

Atlas Insurance comes with the idea of bringing all of these tasks to your fingertips with "Atlas Unify" because modern problems need modern solutions. An app providing all the information to the insured regarding policy detail, intimation of claims, surveyor's information, and claim status is just a click away. Atlas Unify will intimate you 15 days before the policy expires through its renewal feature and keeps you updated with all the latest news and offers related to Atlas Insurance. In addition to it, Atlas Unify gives you the facility to quote for your asset's insurance either you are a registered user or not. Atlas Unify makes it easy for you because apart from your assets Atlas Insurance saves your time too because we care for you.

Leasing App

Connects the booking and verification forms with the backend server using the network library. Also, implement the search and verify functions in it.

# • Islamic App

Islamic App contains the animated Qibla direction compass and prayer time. Complete Quran-e-Pak, which you can access through Para(juz) or also by Surah with translation. It also features online Islamic books and Islamic Quote.

Kids' Education

It contains more than 15 categories and 300+ items for kids to learn and recognize items. It also contains sound and images of 300+ items. It also contains 3 quiz games.